<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on (Machine) Learning log.</title>
    <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on (Machine) Learning log.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamoudad.github.io/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How many patterns are there to lock your android smartphone?</title>
      <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/lock_pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/lock_pattern/</guid>
      <description>If you own an Android smartphone, you are familiar with that pattern you chose to lock your phone with. Every time, you pick your phone and mechanically draw these lines on your screen, connecting the dots to form the unlock pattern.
  Android lockscreen.
   This lock mechanism is more intuitive than using a sequence of numbers (such as PIN), but has its drawbacks, as research papers show how you can efficiently guess the unlock pattern from</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Adversarial Networks can crack your password!</title>
      <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/passgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/passgan/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled upon an article using neural networks that guess passwords. It shows an original application of Generative Adversarial Networks (GAN).
What are GAN?  Generative Adversarial Networks are three words that have been used a lot during the past few years in Artificial Intelligence research. It refers to neural networks that have been trained in the adversarial framework. A neural network is a function with many parameters that can be optimized from assessing the errors the network makes from the expected output, or ground-truth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
