<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on (Machine) Learning log.</title>
    <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on (Machine) Learning log.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamoudad.github.io/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The easy way to synchronize your data.</title>
      <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/rsync/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/rsync/</guid>
      <description>Backing up data is a wise choice, but it can become a hassle for large amount of data.
 Here comes rsync. By reading this article, you will be able to synchronize and backup your data with rsync within one minute!
What is rsync  rsync stands for remote syncrhonization. It is a tool written in C language which lets you synchronize your data seemlessly through a large number of protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynote presentation on Linux</title>
      <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/pdfpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/pdfpc/</guid>
      <description>A great presentation software is a precious tool, even so when working remotely. If you are on MacOS, you will likely want to use Keynote, which has great features such as displaying a presenter view on one screen with a timer while displaying the presentation on another screen. On Linux, however, most PDF readers, like evince if you are using GNOME, have quite limited features for presenting.
 Recently I found about pdfpc, a great tool to do presentations with a PDF document, on Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule random aphorism notifications for your desktop</title>
      <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/random-aphorism-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/random-aphorism-notifications/</guid>
      <description>In times when we lack inspiration, it might help to have a program randomly picking an aphorism for us. An aphorism is a concise expression of a general truth or principle. But you can also use a joke or anything else.
 Let&amp;#39;s see how we can implement this with desktop notifications, python, and cron.
Requirements  You will need these
 python3 with notify2 library. Install it with pip install notify2 a notification daemon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote desktop with Linux client and Windows server</title>
      <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/remote_desktop_linux_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 03:49:04 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/remote_desktop_linux_windows/</guid>
      <description>I just had to set up a remote desktop between Linux and Windows, to find out how intricate of a problem it can become. My goal was to access a Windows desktop from my Linux machine.
Remmina and Windows RDP  I first tried using my go-to software, Remmina client on Linux, using the plugin for connecting to Windows remote desktop protocol (RDP). There were various unsuccessful attempts, with different settings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
