<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grammar on (Machine) Learning log.</title>
    <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/tags/grammar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grammar on (Machine) Learning log.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 02:31:19 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adamoudad.github.io/tags/grammar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bring and take concepts in languages</title>
      <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/language/bring-or-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 02:31:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/language/bring-or-take/</guid>
      <description>Bring or take confusion   I was reading this article on marca.com, when I came upon this sentence in spanish.
Por el momento no hay nada oficial pero varios equipos son los que llevan tiempo pujando por hacerse con sus servicios.  Which made me remember how much I am lost whenever llevar comes out. Should I think &amp;#34;bring&amp;#34; ? &amp;#34;take&amp;#34; ? It bugged me enough to search the internet and find this stackexchange thread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usages of する</title>
      <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/language/suru/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 02:31:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/language/suru/</guid>
      <description>Do you know する? This verb you can use in many case to say &amp;#34;I do stuff&amp;#34;, right ? Yet what if I told you could say far more than just a lame 私はスポーツする?
する basics  We start here with the basics, that is the ~をする form. Use it to express an activity you do regularily.
ラグビーをする。    ~がする  You can express a feeling, a sensation with ~がする.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to use が or は?</title>
      <link>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/language/ga-or-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 02:31:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamoudad.github.io/posts/language/ga-or-ha/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the most fearful grammatical points of any japanese learner during their journey to japanese mastery.
 This article gives some rules that will help confusion and will make you sound like a native.
Relatively to information intended to be delivered 伝えたい情報  は will always precede the information, whereas が will follow it. Similarily, は will always precede an interrogative, while が will follow it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
